The air is so hot, it's hard to breathe.
空气好烫，呼吸起来好困难
So this is the outside of the outside
所以，这就是老师他们说的
the teacher was talking about?
外面的外面哦？
Is this the test?
测试就是这个吗？
If it is,
如果是的话
at least the teachers can't be mad at us for coming here.
至少老师就不会 因为我们来到这里而生气了
You're right.
你说得对
Should we go get the others?
我们该去叫其他人过来吗？
No. Let's take a look first.
不用，我们先查看一下
If this really is the test,
如果这真的就是测试
who goes first will probably count towards our grades.
先走的人很可能会算进我们的成绩
So what are we looking for?
我们要找些什么东西？
Look. The wire fence is broken over there.
你们看，那里的铁丝网破了一个洞
That means there must be another outside beyond there.
这就表示那里一定有另一个外面
Outside the outside of…
外面的外面的…
If we get as far as possible to the final "outside", we'll win.
如果我们尽可能地跑远 找到最终的「外面」，我们就赢了
Win? Win what?
赢了？赢了什么？
Well, I don't know.
这个嘛，我也不知道
Why did they have to make it so hot in here?
他们为什么要把这里弄得这么热？
What? There are big, flying bugs!
搞什么？这里有好大的飞虫
-Yikes! -It's so hard to walk!
-好恶 -路面好难走
I get it!
我懂了
Now it really feels like a test.
现在终于有测试的感觉了
That's it, I'm going back to tell everyone.
我还是想回去告诉大家
Anyway, I'm worried about Tokio.
总之，我很担心时男
Fine.
好吧
But I'm gonna keep going.
但我要继续往前走
What about you, Shiro?
你呢，士郎？
There we go.
放好了
TOKIO Jr. - Jr. C
（小时男，小C）
These two also agree we should return the child to Tokio.
这两人也同意我们该把孩子还给时男
Thank you.
谢谢
How? There are two?
什么？有两个婴儿？
Tokio had twins?
时男生了双胞胎？
It would seem so.
似乎是这样
Dr. Sawatari, which one are we returning to Tokio?
猿渡医生，我们要把哪一个还给时男？
It's all under control. I know which one.
没事的，我知道是哪一个
I put a mark on one of the feet.
我在其中一人的脚上做了记号
I see.
是哦
Then, the one with the mark is…
那么，有记号的是…
That's the one we're returning to Tokio.
我们要把他还给时男
-All right, then-- -Wait, not that one!
-好的，那么… -等等，不是那一个
What?
什么？
So which one is it?
那是哪一个？
The baby without the mark is the one going back to Tokio!
该还给时男的是没有记号的婴儿
Okay, got it.
好的，了解
-Are you okay? -What do you mean?
-你没事吧？ -你是什么意思？
There's no way I'd mix them up!
我绝对不可能搞错
Of course everything is fine!
一切绝对没问题
No. I just meant-- You're bleeding quite a lot.
不是啦，我只是…你流了很多血
-It's only a scratch! -It is?
-那只是擦伤 -是吗？
No, I mean-- Everything is fine!
是说…一切都没问题啦
Then can I leave the one going back to Tokio with you?
那么，我可以把 要还给时男的婴儿交给你吗？
Yes.
可以
After I've checked that the children are safe,
我在确认孩子们都安全了之后
if possible, I'll use this situation
如果可以的话，我会利用这个机会
to execute the Noah Project.
启动诺亚计划
The Noah Project?
诺亚计划？
What is it? Why is it called that?
那是什么？为什么要取这种名字？
Does nobody know about it?
有人知道这件事吗？
I apologize.
很抱歉
I named it in the spur of the moment.
我只是刚好想到了这个名字
It's the plan to protect the children.
这个计划是为了保护孩子们
MITA CONDO
（三田公寓）
It's not as if we agreed exactly what day she'd be back.
又不是说我们讲好了她哪一天会回来
If I finally found the guy I'd been searching for for five years,
如果我终于找到了我找了五年的人
we'd probably spend the whole night talking.
我们很可能也会一整晚聊不停吧
I guess we'd have a few drinks--
我想我们会喝个几杯…
Well, I can't drink, but anyway.
是说，我不会喝酒，但总之…
We'd probably end up sleeping all the next day.
我们很可能会一起睡到天亮
But not coming back for another night
但过了一天还不回来
is a little…
就有一点…
Oops. The bottom's burnt.
咦？锅底烧焦了
-Hey you! -You there! Stop!
-喂！ -你给我站住
You can't go in there without authorization.
没得到授权，你不能进去
A woman came this way two nights ago.
有个女人在两天前的晚上来到这里
She hasn't returned, so I've come to get her.
她还没回来，所以我来找她
What? Isn't she Inazaki's old flame?
什么？她不是稻崎的老情人吗？
He told us not to let anyone in.
他告诉我们不能让任何人进来
Go get authorization from the Ministry.
去复兴省那里取得授权吧
They must've rekindled their passion!
他们一定旧情复燃了啦
I was in the plant all day yesterday,
我昨天一整天都待在工厂里
and they were just too much for me.
我真的是受不了他们两个了
She'll come back eventually. Just wait a bit--
她最终会回去的啦，你再等一下…
Hey, you! We said no!
喂！我们说了不行！
Hey, wait…
等等…
Wait!
等等
LARGE FILTRATION PLANT
（大型过滤厂）
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
（仅限授权人士）
Who are you? You got authorization?
你是谁？你得到授权了吗？
A bandit?
土匪？
Since Haruki's a deep sleeper.
因为春希一向都睡得很熟
What was that?
那是怎么回事？
They can't possibly be my own memories of seeing myself sleeping.
看到我自己在睡觉，不可能是我的记忆
But…
但是…
I can recall all of those memories of Sis.
我能清楚记得姐所有的记忆
Was that one of my sister's memories lingering in her body?
那也是姐挥之不去的记忆吗？
She could still be alive
她很可能还活着
somewhere in this body.
活在她身体里的某个地方
Maybe my mind is syncing with her body
或许我的思想与她的身体同步了
and I'm slowly turning into my sister.
所以我渐渐地转变成我姐姐
That would be great. I'd love that.
那就太好了，我希望是这样
It hurts.
好痛
What was that look on Robin's face?
露敏的表情是怎么回事？
Something feels off.
有点不太对劲
That expression he had when he saw me. What did it…
他看到我时那一瞬间的表情，那是…
Stop.
不行了
I don't want to think about anything.
我不想再思考这些了
I just want to follow orders.
我只想听从命令
Like Maru.
就跟小丸一样
Maru!
小丸
Save me!
救我
Sis?
姐？
Maru!
小丸
Hey! Somebody!
来人啊
Maru! Maru!
小丸，小丸
What? You're alone?
什么？就你一个人吗？
You underestimate me!
你太小看我了
I heard all about you.
我听说过很多关于你的事
Aren't you the guy Haruki's guarding?
你就是春希在保护的那个人吧？
Did Haruki also take care of you down there?
春希也一并照顾了你的下体吗？
What the hell are you looking at?
你到底在看什么东西？
Don't mess with me, you damn kid!
你这个死小孩，别惹我
THE JOURNEY CONTINUES AND BEGINS
（旅程的延续和开始）
Tokio? Tokio!
时男？时男？
Let me.
让我来
Tokio! I'm opening the door!
时男，我要开门咯
Tokio!
时男
Are you hurt?
你受伤了吗？
No.
没有
What happened?
发生了什么事？
We're trying to find out.
我们正在调查
But there is something more important I have to tell you.
但我有一件更重要的事要告诉你
This baby is your child.
这个婴儿是你的孩子
What?
什么？
This baby grew inside you.
你的肚子里怀了这个孩子
You gave birth to it, Tokio.
你生下了他，时男
This baby is yours and Kona's.
这个婴儿是你和小奈的孩子
We'll all think together about how to raise the child,
我们会一起想办法带大这个孩子
but we thought we should at least tell you the facts.
但我们认为至少要让你知道真相
This is
这是…
a baby?
一个婴儿？
That thing you took out of me!
你们从我体内拿走的东西
Exactly.
没错
That's what all the hard work was for.
这就是你千辛万苦所得到的成果
So cute.
好可爱
Does Kona know?
小奈知道吗？
-We need to show Kona. -That's right.
-我们得让小奈看看他 -没错
Let's go and find him.
我们去找他吧
I won't give up. Not until I win!
在我赢之前，我绝不放弃
Director!
园长
You've returned?
你回来了？
As you can see, my timing is spot on.
如你所见，我回来得正是时候
But wait… You can walk?
但是，等等…你可以走路？
Tokio!
时男
Give the baby here.
把婴儿给我
Director!
园长
Let's treat your wounds first.
我们先帮你疗伤吧
Then I'll give you the baby.
然后我就会把婴儿给你
What? Never!
什么？才不要
No, Tokio!
不行，时男
Hey, Mina!
美娜
Take the baby away!
把婴儿带走
Understood.
好的
-Please stop! -Do it!
-拜托，住手 -动手
What is this?
那是什么东西？
One of their faces is the same as yours.
其中一个人跟你长得一模一样
Outside of the outside?
外面的外面？
There is an outside beyond here.
这里之外还有一个外面
-What are you good at? -Run away.
-你擅长什么？ -快跑
What's happening?
怎么回事？
Stay away! Nobody come near me!
走开，不准任何人靠近我
No, wait!
不行，等等
Kona.
小奈
You
你
and I,
和我
what exactly are we?
我们究竟是什么？
I thought we'd be back at the wire fence by now.
我还以为我们已经回到铁丝网了
I don't see it anywhere.
完全没看到任何铁丝网
That's weird.
那就怪了
We went straight ahead and walked straight coming back, right?
我们是直直往前走 然后又直直走回来，对吧？
I thought so too.
我也以为是这样
Let's keep going straight a bit more.
我们再直直往前走一点吧
Even if we're going in the wrong direction…
就算我们走错方向了
OUTSIDE OF THE OUTSIDE WIRE FENCE - OUTSIDE - SCHOOL
（外面的外面） （铁丝网，外面，学校）
…if we keep going straight, we should reach it eventually.
如果我们走的是直线 我们终究会看到铁丝网才对
Then we can follow the fence to get back.
然后我们就能沿着铁丝网走回去
You're right!
你说得对
You're really talkative when it's just the two of us.
只有我们两个人的时候，你就变得好多话
Am I?
是吗？
Hey, did we walk past a place this steep?
我们刚刚经过了这么陡的斜坡吗？
I can hear water.
我听到水声了
I don't hear anything.
我什么都没听到
Let's go see.
我们去看看
Yeah. Anything but another tree would make a good landmark.
好，如果有树木之外的东西 那会是个好地标
That's so much water.
这里有好多水啊
If it's flowing away from the school,
如果是朝着与学校相反的方向流过去的话
then the school must be upstream.
那么学校就会在上游
Makes sense.
有道理
Mimihime!
弥美姬
Shiro! Shiro!
士郎，士郎
Stop! Don't move!
慢点，别动
Why?
为什么？
Why did you do that just to save me?
你为什么要为了救我而做出这种事？
Because I…
因为我…
When I think about you--
当我想到你的时候…
Wait, no.
等等，不对
When I think about your body--
当我想到你的身体时…
No, that's not it.
也不是这样
I really love you, Mimihime.
我真的很爱你，弥美姬
If it means I can save you,
如果那么做能够救你一命
I don't care how many times I get cut to shreds.
我碎尸万段几百次都没关系
If that's what you want.
如果那是你想要的
Or rather,
或者…
if you'll let me.
如果你同意我这么做
Stop!
住手
That's enough. Stop it.
够了，住手
Please.
拜托你
Don't kill Robin.
别杀了露敏
Sorry.
对不起
I'm so weak.
我好弱
Everything I believed in was all a lie.
我所相信的一切都只是个谎言
I don't even know who I really am anymore.
我甚至再也不知道我是谁了
If you took me apart and put me back together again,
如果你把我拆开，然后再组合起来
I'd probably disappear
我很可能会消失
and turn into my sister instead.
转而变成我姐姐
Sis.
姐
You've already--
你已经…
It feels like you've already dumped me three or four times,
我觉得你已经甩了我三四次了
but let me say it again.
但让我再说一次
If you don't like it, just throw that rock into the river and I'll stop.
如果你不想听，你就把石头丢进河里 我就会住口
I'm kinda--
我有点…
I'm into girls.
我喜欢的是女生
If I'd have met the real Haruki,
如果我能够认识真正的春希
we probably would've been friends,
我们很可能会成为朋友
but I don't think I'd have fallen for him in that way.
但我不认为我会喜欢上他
And since you really like Kiriko,
既然你这么喜欢桐子
she must be a really great person.
她一定是个很了不起的人
Yeah.
对呀
That's one thing I'm certain of.
这件事我很肯定
But I don't know if I'd have fallen for Kiriko either.
但我也不确定我是否会喜欢上桐子
Hey…
喂…
you're the one I'm in love with!
我喜欢的人是你
Not Haruki or Kiriko. It's you!
不是春希，也不是桐子，是你
You're strong!
你很强悍
You always take care of me! And the way you see things is always right.
你总是照顾着我 你对事情的看法总是对的
Without your help,
没有你的帮助
I wouldn't be able to drive, cook or even reheat food.
我就不会开车、煮饭 甚至也不会加热食物
I can't do anything right without you.
没有你，我什么都做不好
But if you're ever in danger,
但如果你遇上了危险
I'll protect you!
我会保护你
I'll make sure
我一定会…
to always keep you safe.
好好保护你
What?
什么？
What's the point of my existence
如果受到保护的人是我
if I'm the one getting protected?
我的存在还有什么意义？
I know, I know!
我知道，我知道
You're my guard.
你是我的保镖
Hey! Your snot is getting on me!
你的鼻涕沾到我身上了啦
When I was a kid…
当我还小的时候
…I used to hiccup like this every time I cried.
我每次哭的时候都会像这样打嗝
It takes me back.
这让我想到了从前
Now I've met him and finished what I set out to do,
我现在找到他了，达成了我的目标
I don't need this.
我不需要这个了
Robin Inazaki,
稻崎露敏
if I ever see you again,
如果再让我见到你
I'm going to
我就会…
kill you!
杀了你
What do you mean nobody's here?
这里一个人都没有是什么意思？
Not sure.
不确定
I couldn't get in contact with anyone at the plant.
工厂里的人，我一个都联络不上
When I came to see what was going on, it was deserted.
我到这里查看情况时，就空无一人了
Is this coffee?
这是咖啡吗？
What a waste.
太浪费了吧
Sir! I found a set of keys.
长官，我发现了一串钥匙
And those are bloodstains?
那是血迹吗？
What happened here?
这里发生了什么事？
This is the only locked room.
这是唯一上锁的房间
Open it.
打开
It's dark.
好黑
What is that?
那是什么东西？
A monster is attached to a human?
依附在人类身上的怪物？
That woman!
那个女人
I remember she registered as a resident about three months ago.
我记得她在三个月前完成了居民注册
Her mind is completely gone.
她的心智完全消失了
What the hell was Inazaki doing here?
稻崎到底在这里做些什么勾当？
-Okay. Shall we go? -You sure?
-好了，要出发了吗？ -你确定？
I can't stay depressed forever.
我总不能一直闷闷不乐吧
Our goal is Heaven.
我们的目的地是天国
Our mission hasn't changed.
我们的任务没变
Besides, you'll protect me when it's dangerous, right?
况且，遇到危险的时候 你会保护我，对吧？
I will.
对啦
And you'll save me when I'm in trouble.
当我遇上麻烦的时候，你会救我
Again?
又来了？
It's so embarrassing to stall just when we're making a dramatic exit!
就在我们要徜徉而去的时候抛锚 也太丢脸了吧
There's no one here, so it doesn't count!
这里一个人都没有，所以不算
It's not my fault!
又不是我的错
Go complain to the Kirukomaru!
去找贵留子小丸客诉